Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erica.
我是Erica。
And today we're bringing you the next part of our suspense series, The New Guy in Town.
今天我们带来悬疑系列的下一个部分，《镇上的新面孔》。
That's right.
没错。
So we know that Armando wasn't really a vampire, that he was just acting.
所以我们知道Armando其实不是吸血鬼，他只是在演戏。
And the women aren't quite what they seem in this dialogue.
而在这段对话里，那些女人也不是表面看起来的样子。
In the last one, something happened and she transformed into some sort of, I don't know,
在上一集里，发生了点事，她变成了某种，我也不知道，
creature, right?
生物，对吧？
Like monster.
像怪物一样。
Right.
对。
So now let's see what happens.
现在我们来看看发生了什么。
So we're not going to preview any vocabulary this time.
这次我们不预览任何词汇。
Let's just listen to the dialogue and see what happens.
直接听对话，看看会发生什么。
What the heck is going on?
这到底是怎么回事？
Did you see that?
你看到了吗？
What was that thing?
那是什么东西？
I don't know.
我不知道。
I'm just glad we made it out.
我很高兴我们逃出来了。
Look, there's a police car.
看，有辆警车。
Help!
救命！
Please, please stop!
请，请停车！
Howdy, ma'am.
你好，女士。
What seems to be the problem?
出什么问题了？
Is this man bothering you?
这个男人在骚扰你吗？
Officer, officer.
警官，警官。
There is like a witch creature back there.
后面有个像女巫一样的怪物。
We tied her up, but she broke free and she was about to have us for dinner.
我们把她绑起来了，但她挣脱了，还差点把我们当晚餐。
Okay, calm down.
好了，冷静点。
Calm down.
冷静点。
Let me see your eyes, please.
请让我看看你的眼睛。
Have you been drinking tonight, son?
今晚喝酒了吗，小伙子？
We're telling the truth.
我们说的是实话。
She's in there.
她就在里面。
We suspected her being a kidnapper or a rapist, but it turns out she's an alien or something.
我们怀疑她是绑架犯或强奸犯，但结果她是个外星人什么的。
Okay, calm down.
好了，冷静点。
Calm down.
冷静点。
Let me see your eyes, please.
请让我看看你的眼睛。
Seriously.
说真的。
Are you going to help us out or not?
你到底帮不帮我们？
Okay.
好吧。
Let's go have a look, shall we?
我们去看看，好吗？
Hello?
喂？
Is anyone in there?
里面有人吗？
Be careful.
小心点。
She might be hiding.
她可能躲起来了。
It's perfectly safe.
这里绝对安全。
There isn't anyone.
没人在。
I don't think things are turning out very well for our housewives and Armand.
我觉得我们的主妇们和阿曼德的情况不太妙。
Apparently, the police officer is not going to make it to the next episode.
显然，那位警察是赶不上下一集了。
Uh-oh.
哎呀。
All right.
好了。
So, we saw some really great vocabulary and even though it's kind of a scary story, there
我们学到了一些很棒的词汇，虽然这是个有点吓人的故事，但
is a lot of things we can learn.
有很多东西可以学。
So why don't we take a look at it now in Language Takeaway.
那我们不如现在就在“语言精华”环节来看看吧。
Language Takeaway.
语言精华。
Well, we're going to look at five words and phrases here and the first one, they described
我们要看五个单词和短语，第一个，他们把这个女人描述成一种
this woman as a kind of creature.
生物。
Creature.
All right.
好的。
So, what exactly is a creature?
那么，生物到底是什么？
Well, a creature can be any animal.
嗯，生物可以是任何动物。
Any animal?
任何动物？
Yeah, like from a mouse to a bird to an insect or a bug.
对，比如从老鼠到鸟，再到昆虫或小虫子。
So I can say a bird is a flying creature.
所以可以说鸟是一种会飞的生物。
Exactly.
没错。
All right.
好的。
You can also use it to mean an unknown and scary animal.
你也可以用它来表示一种未知且吓人的动物。
So there's a creature under my bed.
所以我床底下有个生物。
Yes.
是的。
Or some type of creature was attacking me.
或者某种生物在攻击我。
Okay.
好的。
So, a creature can be any sort of living thing or animal.
所以，生物可以是任何有生命的东西或动物。
Exactly.
没错。
Yep.
嗯。
All right.
好的。
What about our next one?
下一个词呢？
Well, the creature broke free from some ropes.
嗯，那个生物挣脱了绳子。
All right.
好的。
So, to break free.
那么，关于“挣脱”。
Break free.
挣脱。
Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
And what does that mean?
那是什么意思？
When you break free, you escape from something that stops you moving.
当你挣脱时，你从阻碍你行动的东西中逃脱出来。
Okay.
好的。
So, you have the ability to move again.
所以，你又能行动了。
Yes.
是的。
You break free from maybe ropes.
你可能是从绳索中挣脱出来。
Or chains.
或者锁链。
Or even a relationship.
甚至是一段关系。
Okay.
好的。
So, I can say, oh, I finally broke free from that awful relationship.
所以，我可以说，哦，我终于摆脱了那段糟糕的关系。
Mm-hmm.
嗯哼。
Now, that's quite interesting the way we can use this in different ways.
现在，我们能用它表达不同意思，这挺有趣的。
So why don't we take a look at some examples now?
那我们不如现在来看一些例子吧？
Example one.
例子一。
Somebody tied up the dog, but he is trying to break free.
有人把狗拴住了，但它正试图挣脱。
Example two.
例子二。
I'm glad that I broke free from that horrible relationship.
我很高兴摆脱了那段可怕的关系。
Example three.
例子三。
I want to break free from all my daily responsibilities.
我想摆脱所有日常责任。
Okay.
好的。
So break free, it's clear now.
所以“挣脱”，现在清楚了。
Mm-hmm.
嗯哼。
So why don't we move on to our next word?
那我们不如继续看下一个词？
They thought that maybe this creature was a kidnapper.
他们以为这个生物可能是个绑架犯。
Kidnapper.
绑架犯。
Okay.
好的。
So this is?
所以这是？
A criminal.
一个罪犯。
So, a kidnapper is a criminal.
所以，绑架犯是罪犯。
Yep.
是的。
All right.
好的。
And what exactly does a kidnapper do?
那绑架犯具体做什么？
A kidnapper takes someone to a place and keeps them there against their will.
绑架犯把某人带到某个地方，并违背其意愿关押在那里。
Against their will.
违背其意愿。
With force or violence.
使用武力或暴力。
All right.
好吧。
So, I guess that makes sense, right?
所以，我想这说得通，对吧？
Because the word has kid in it.
因为这个词里有“kid”（孩子）。
Yeah.
是的。
So, it can take children.
所以，它可以指绑架儿童。
Yes.
对。
But it can be also, you can kidnap an adult.
但也可以，你可以绑架一个成年人。
Yes, that's true.
是的，没错。
All right.
好吧。
So, this word can actually be used in three different ways.
所以，这个词实际上可以有三种不同的用法。
So we saw a kidnapper, right?
我们看到了“kidnapper”（绑架者），对吧？
Okay, that is the person.
好的，那是指人。
Yeah.
是的。
And the verb, to kidnap.
还有动词，“to kidnap”（绑架）。
Okay.
好的。
Or a noun describing an action, a kidnapping.
或者一个描述动作的名词，“a kidnapping”（绑架事件）。
A kidnapping.
绑架事件。
Very good.
非常好。
Yeah, a kidnapping took place today.
是的，今天发生了一起绑架事件。
Okay.
好的。
So, very interesting word.
所以，这是一个非常有趣的词。
And of course, it's illegal to be a kidnapper.
当然，当绑架者是违法的。
Yes.
是的。
But this word is also very serious and it's also a crime, right?
但这个词也很严肃，而且也是一种犯罪，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
A rapist.
强奸犯。
Okay.
好的。
So, that is a person that...
所以，那是指一个人...
Who forces someone to have sex.
强迫别人发生性关系的人。
Okay.
好的。
So, again, against their will.
所以，再次强调，是违背他们的意愿。
Right.
对。
Like a kidnapper.
就像绑架者一样。
Exactly.
完全正确。
Okay.
好的。
And the verb would be...
而动词会是...
To rape.
强奸。
To rape someone.
强奸某人。
Okay.
好的。
So, on the lighter side, we heard the police officer say something in a very strange way.
所以，轻松一点来说，我们听到警察用一种很奇怪的方式说了句话。
He said, let me see your eyes, please.
他说，请让我看看你的眼睛。
Okay.
好的。
And this is an interesting phrase.
这是一个有趣的短语。
It's a sound made from pushing two words together.
这是由两个单词连读发出的声音。
Right.
对。
So, let me.
所以，“let me”。
Why don't we hear a few more examples of this and see if we can figure out what are the
我们不如再听几个例子，看看能不能弄清楚是哪两个单词。
two words.
两个单词。
Example one.
例子一。
Let me have a look inside the car.
让我看看车里。
Example two.
例子二。
Let me go out tonight, dad.
爸爸，今晚让我出去吧。
Example three.
例子三。
Let me think about it and I'll give you an answer tomorrow.
让我想想，明天给你答复。
So, basically, let me is...
所以，基本上，“let me”就是……
Let me.
“Let me”。
Yeah.
是的。
Let me have that pen.
把那支笔给我。
Okay.
好的。
Let me see.
让我看看。
Now, we do this also with other words, right?
我们也会用其他单词这样连读，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
Another example would be give me.
另一个例子是“give me”。
Give me.
“Give me”。
Yeah.
是的。
Give me.
“Give me”。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So, an interesting thing.
所以，有趣的是。
It's not proper English, right?
这不是标准的英语，对吧？
No.
不是。
You wouldn't really write it this way.
你不会真的这样写。
Or find it in the dictionary.
或者在字典里找到它。
But it's really common when people speak.
但人们在说话时真的很常见。
And actually, it's more likely that you'll say let me, give me, than let me, give me.
实际上，你更可能说“let me”、“give me”，而不是“let me”、“give me”。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
So, I think now it's time for us to listen to our dialogue for the second time.
那么，我想现在是时候让我们第二次听对话了。
And then we'll come back and look at some other phrases that we saw in our dialogue.
然后我们会回来看看对话中出现的其他短语。
What the heck is going on?
这到底是怎么回事？
Did you see that?
你看到了吗？
What was that thing?
那是什么东西？
I don't know.
我不知道。
I'm just glad we made it out.
我很庆幸我们逃出来了。
Look, there's a police car.
看，有辆警车。
Help!
救命！
Please stop.
请停下。
Howdy, ma'am.
你好，女士。
What seems to be the problem?
出了什么问题？
Is this man bothering you?
这个男人在骚扰你吗？
Officer!
警官！
There is like a witch creature back there.
后面有个像女巫一样的生物。
We tied her up, but she broke free.
我们把她绑起来了，但她挣脱了。
And she was about to have us for dinner.
她差点把我们当晚餐吃了。
Okay.
好的。
Calm down.
冷静点。
Let me see your eyes, please.
请让我看看你的眼睛。
Have you been drinking tonight, son?
今晚喝酒了吗，小伙子？
We are telling the truth.
我们说的是实话。
She's in there.
她就在里面。
We suspected her of being a kidnapper or rapist, but it turns out she's an alien or something.
我们怀疑她是绑架犯或强奸犯，但结果发现她是个外星人什么的。
Okay.
好的。
Calm down.
冷静点。
Let me see your eyes, please.
请让我看看你的眼睛。
Seriously.
说真的。
Are you going to help us or not?
你到底帮不帮我们？
Okay.
好的。
Let's go have a look, shall we?
我们进去看看，好吗？
Hello?
喂？
Is anyone in here?
有人在这里吗？
Be careful.
小心点。
She might be hiding.
她可能躲起来了。
It's perfectly safe.
非常安全。
There isn't anyone.
没人在里面。
We're going to look at two phrases now in Fluency Builder that you might hear when you're
现在我们来看“流利度构建”中的两个短语，你在谈论犯罪时可能会听到。
talking about a crime.
流利度构建。
Fluency Builder.
So the first phrase that we're going to look at is, what the heck is going on?
我们要看的第一个短语是“这到底是怎么回事？”
What the heck is going on?
这到底是怎么回事？
Okay.
好的。
So this is just asking what's happening, right?
所以这只是问发生了什么，对吧？
Right.
对。
So this is a very strong way of saying what's happening.
这是一种非常强烈的表达方式，表示“发生了什么”。
Yeah.
是的。
What really is happening?
到底发生了什么？
Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
Now, why do they say, what the heck?
那么，他们为什么说“what the heck”？
What is heck?
“heck”是什么？
Well, heck is sort of a polite way of saying hell.
嗯，“heck”是“hell”的一种礼貌说法。
Okay.
好的。
So instead of saying, what the hell is going on?
所以不说“what the hell is going on？”
What the heck is going on?
而是说“what the heck is going on？”
Now, why do you do this?
为什么要这样做？
Because especially in American English, we don't like to talk about religious words.
因为特别是在美式英语中，我们不喜欢谈论宗教词汇。
So like hell and God and Jesus, these things are impolite in American English.
所以像“hell”、“God”和“Jesus”这些词在美式英语中是不礼貌的。
Right.
对。
You don't want to offend anyone.
你不想冒犯任何人。
That's why we would have other words like, oh my gosh.
这就是为什么我们会有其他词，比如“oh my gosh”。
For oh my God.
代替“oh my God”。
Or geez.
或者“geez”。
Instead of Jesus.
代替“Jesus”。
Right.
对。
Okay.
好的。
So that is an interesting thing and of course, it is a little bit of a sensitive topic among
所以这是一件有趣的事情，当然，在某些人中这是一个有点敏感的话题。
some people.
所以最好使用这些同义词。
So that's why it's better to just use these synonyms.
是的。
Yes.
好的。
Okay.
And what about our next phrase?
那我们的下一个短语呢？
So they suspected her of being a kidnapper.
所以他们怀疑她是绑架犯。
Okay.
好的。
So suspected her of being a kidnapper.
所以“怀疑她是绑架犯”。
Yeah.
是的。
So I suspect someone of being something.
所以我怀疑某人是某种人。
So I suspect she is an alien.
所以我怀疑她是外星人。
Right.
对。
I suspect him of being a liar.
我怀疑他是个骗子。
Okay.
好的。
So what about to suspect?
那么“suspect”是什么意思？
What does that mean exactly?
它到底是什么意思？
To think something that is true, but not be 100% sure.
认为某事是真的，但不是百分之百确定。
So you can say, I think she is a kidnapper.
所以你可以说“我认为她是绑架犯”。
Yep.
是的。
Oh, I suspect her of being a kidnapper.
哦，我怀疑她是绑架犯。
Interesting.
有意思。
Why don't we hear a few more examples?
我们为什么不听几个例子呢？
Example one.
例子一。
The police suspected him of being a bank robber.
警察怀疑他是银行抢劫犯。
Example two.
例子二。
We suspect our dog is responsible for this mess.
我们怀疑我们的狗造成了这团乱。
Example three.
例子三。
The neighborhood suspected that our neighbor was selling drugs.
邻居们怀疑我们的邻居在卖毒品。
All right.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
So we've seen a lot of vocab.
所以我们看到了很多词汇。
We've seen these phrases.
我们看到了这些短语。
So I think it's time for us to listen to our dialogue for the last time, and then we'll
所以我想是时候最后一次听我们的对话了，然后我们会回来再聊一会儿。
come back and talk a little bit more.
这到底是怎么回事？
What the heck is going on?
Did you see that?
你看到了吗？
What was that thing?
那是什么东西？
I don't know.
我不知道。
I'm just glad we made it out.
我很庆幸我们逃出来了。
Look, there's a police car.
看，有辆警车。
Help!
救命！
Please, please stop!
请，请停下！
Howdy, ma'am.
你好，女士。
What, uh, seems to be the problem?
呃，出了什么问题？
Is this man bothering you?
这个男人在骚扰你吗？
Officer, officer.
警官，警官。
There is, like, a witch creature back there.
后面有个像女巫一样的生物。
We tied her up, but she broke free, and she was about to have us for dinner.
我们把她绑起来了，但她挣脱了，她差点把我们当晚餐吃了。
Okay, calm down, calm down.
好的，冷静点，冷静点。
Let me see your eyes, please.
请让我看看你的眼睛。
Have you been drinking tonight, son?
今晚喝酒了吗，小伙子？
We're telling the truth.
我们说的是实话。
She's in there.
她就在里面。
We suspected her being a kidnapper or a rapist, but turns out she's an alien or something.
我们怀疑她是绑架犯或强奸犯，但结果发现她是个外星人什么的。
Okay, calm down, calm down.
好的，冷静点，冷静点。
Let me see your eyes, please.
请让我看看你的眼睛。
Ugh, seriously.
呃，说真的。
Are you going to help us out or not?
你到底帮不帮我们？
Okay.
好的。
Let's go have a look, shall we?
我们进去看看，好吗？
Hello?
喂？
Is anyone in there?
有人在里面吗？
Be careful!
小心点！
She might be hiding!
她可能躲起来了！
It's perfectly safe.
非常安全。
There isn't anyone.
没人在里面。
You're mil Taking too long.
你花的时间太长了。
Okay, well, Marco, we're coming near the end of this series, aren't we?
好的，马可，我们快到这个系列的结尾了，对吧？
Yes, exactly.
是的，没错。
It's a short series, but what do you think happens or how do you think the series ends?
这是一个短系列，但你觉得会发生什么，或者这个系列会如何结束？
What is really going on?
到底发生了什么？
A mystery here at EnglishPod.
EnglishPod 这里的一个谜团。
So we want to hear from you.
所以我们想听听你的意见。
What do you think is going to happen?
你觉得会发生什么？
Exactly.
没错。
You can find it at EnglishPod.com where you can leave us your questions, your comments,
你可以在 EnglishPod.com 上找到它，在那里你可以留下你的问题、评论，甚至可能是你的想法，不仅针对这节课，也针对任何你想听的课程。
or even maybe your ideas, not only for this lesson, but for any lesson that you would
没错。
like to hear.
好了，各位，我们很高兴你下载了这节课，记得查看我们的网站。
That's right.
没错。
Well, guys, we're happy that you downloaded this lesson and remember to check out our
好了，各位，我们很高兴你下载了这节课，记得查看我们的网站。
website.
直到下次，感谢收听，再见。
Until next time, thanks for listening and goodbye.